# **Nicole Moseley**

## Computer Programmer/Contractor - Viva, inc

Elgin, IL - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Nicole-Moseley/cfb43898c1874a50

I am a full-stack programmer with Leadership experience and over 12 years of programming experience. Willing to relocate to: Grand Junction, CO
Authorized to work in the US for any employer

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Computer Programmer/Contractor

Viva, inc - Chicago, IL - September 2016 to Present

Programmed a Wordpress theme from scratch with PHP, Javascript, CSS, and HTML.

- Learned and worked on the infrastructure behind ACCC's Identity and Access Management. This encompasses a mysql database (IAM) and some older DB2 infrastructure. Worked on CentOS and Redhat vitually with Ubuntu Linux on my laptop. Experience installing and using KVM and VirtualBox with CentOS. Apache installation and configuration.
- Programmed using Catalyst, an MVC web application framework in Perl. Designed and implemented a Billing Application using this framework. Re-wrote module used in Catalyst module, UIC::DBIC::IAM using DBIC (DbIx Class). Used Perl's Template::Toolkit. Originally wrote this as a separate perl module, but rewrote to fit within current module. Designed application to output CSV files and template (html) files using Catalyst::View::CSV.
- Re-wrote a emergency alert for webpages to be used by U of I's Peoria division. Used Perl, Javascript and Perl's Template class.
- Wrote a Perl script as a cron job for automatically updating multiple Wordpress Websites. Added a subroutine to a former Perl module UIC::Webhost in doing this.
- Used UIC's REST interface to IAM infrastructure and used Outlook Calendar REST API
- Git versions control and workflow experience. Experience dumping Mysql database onto new test virtual server. Chef infrastructure and some configuration.
- Experience moving the management of Services off of old DB2 infrastructure onto IAM mysql database. Tabular creation and programming Catalyst to manage a new Service Type and modifying the view. Experience modifying IAM-web with Javascript/Dojo. Used FastCGI in testing on development environment.
- Currently working on moving UIC's Event Calendar off of old systems determined to be decommissioned soon. Working toward a new backend which is currently in Oracle. Working on the use of Patternlab for Wordpress backend.
- Set up a test Wordpress site using Shibboleth SSO for login for a future Event Calendar.
- Wrote a cron task for updating a service connecting to Active Directory with RabbitM

### **Computer Consultatnt/Programmer**

GreatLakes IT, inc - March 2015 to August 2016

Formerly lead programmer here, although I came back as a consultant remotely. Was a Full Lamp Stack programmer with OOP using PHP. Also did Perl scripting and Apache installation and configuration.

- Mysql, MSSQL database structure, design, modification
- Perl scripting for task automation
- Joomla Content Management, Wordpress development
- MVC with Codeigniter (and PHP)
- Javascript for Adobe Illustrator

#### **Database Programmer**

Chicago Public Schools with Quantum Crossings, Inc - February 2011 to March 2015

Sole programmer for telecommunications team. Lead others on program usage.

- Managed over 12 programs for EMS the Expense Management System
- Consult with managerial, engineering and technical personnel to clarify program intent, identify problems and manage changes.
- PHP Web Application development and maintenance
- Oracle, MSSQL, Mysql database design, development, modification
- Data modeling and back-end development
- Front-end development with Javascript, PHP, Jquery and Ajax, HTML, CSS.
- Administered the ETL

#### **Lead Programmer**

GreatLakes IT, inc - November 2005 to February 2011

Led initiatives for myself and two other programmers/IT specialists.

- Designed websites and determined workload for other programmers
- PHP, Perl, Java and C# design, development and modifications
- Instructed others on Content Management with Joomla
- Mysql and MSSQL database design and development

#### **Senior Programmer**

Accenture - November 2005 to February 2011

Led weekly meetings with client as to client needs and requirements.

- Reduced execution time of a C batch program on 36 processors by 67%
- Enhanced security on production server
- Developed numerous Perl programs, e.g. programs for converting 8 GB from binary to asci.
- Wrote application for migrating data in and out of source control
- Tested Java code with Apache Tomcat
- Taught myself Abinitio and did some data warehousing

#### **Engineering Intern**

Eisolution, inc - May 2004 to June 2004

Website development with J2SDK, Apache Tomcat, and Netbeans IDE

Database design with Postgresql

#### **EDUCATION**

## Bachelor of Science in (BS.) Computer Science Engineering

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign - Urbana-Champaign, IL 2003